Joseph Moore

Software Engineer

Ву Request

 □ joseph@thatjoemoore.com

 ⊕ github.com/ThatJoeMoore

 dev.to/ThatJoeMoore

Objective

Innovative programmer looking for opportunity on a collaborative team that prioritizes sustainable innovation and software craftsmanship. With 11 years experience, I am looking for the freedom to solve real problems in an open, honest forum with a healthy work/life balance.

Accomplishments & Notable Projects

- > Rapidly delivered a university-wide integration with a new, API-driven payment solution.
- > Guided transition from a monolithic, Java/Spring stack to a simpler, Kotlin-based microservice model.
- > Developed tooling to simplify deployment of applications to Amazon Web Services (hdl.thatjoemoore.com).
- > Built tooling in Kotlin to enable rapid development of REST APIs that conform to the University API standard (kuapi.thatjoemoore.com).
- > Pioneered the BYU Web Brand framework and a git-based CDN that allowed for fast pageloads and timely updates and bugfixes (btc.thatjoemoore.com and cdn.thatjoemoore.com).
- > Two-time recipient of the BYU Staff and Administrative Employee Recognition Award.

Professional Experience

Software Developer, Brigham Young University Office of IT

May 2012 - Present

- Lead small project teams in design, development, and maintenance of full-stack, event- and API-driven applications in Java, Kotlin, Node.js, and Vue.js.
- > Collaborate with campus community to design and implement a cross-framework web brand.
- > Advocate best practices as part of cross-functional working groups.
- > Architect and craft shared infrastructure and deployment tooling.
- Mentor junior developers and student developers in all aspects of software development.

Student Developer, Brigham Young University Office of IT

August 2008 - May 2012

- > Overhauled the BYU Android App, taking it from a quick minimum viable product to a feature-rich, maintainable application.
- Developed UIs for Web (Java, Spring) and Desktop (Java Swing).
- Build backend web APIs in Java (Spring, Hibernate) using SOAP and RESTful styles.

Passions and Side Projects

- > SAINTCON cybersecurity conference high scorere in the Hacker's Challenge and joint winner of the Wireless Hunt.
- > Kobble a work-in-progress exploration of a different way of doing Dependency Injection in Kotlin (kbl.thatjoemoore.com).
- > University API Winter Workshop.

Top Skills

Backend Development

Java, Kotlin, Scala, Node.js, Go

Web Development

HTML, Javascript, CSS, Vue.js, Svelte, Web Components, JSP/Servlet

API Development

REST, SOAP, JSON, XML, OpenAPI/Swagger

Automated Testing

JUnit, Mocha, Jest, Runscope, Selenium, Puppeteer

Architectures

Microservices, Asynchronous Events, Web APIs

Data Persistence

SQL, Hibernate, JDBC, DynamoDB, Google Cloud Datastore, S3

Infrastructure

AWS, GCP, Serverless, Linux, Docker, Infrastructure As Code

Engineering Practices

Agile, CI/CD, Test-Driven Development, Domain-Driven Design

Security & Compliance

PCI-DSS, FERPA, HIPAA, Web Application Security

Education & Certifications

Brigham Young University

2005-2006 & 2008-2012

Completed 96 credit hours toward BS in Mechanical Engineering

AWS Certified Solutions Architect

Associate Level

Valid through December 2019